<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[cirQWizard]]></title>
  <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//"/>
  <updated>2014-09-29T17:51:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://cirqwizard.org//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Simon Salykov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.5.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/09/29/version-1-dot-5-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-29T17:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/09/29/version-1-dot-5-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.5.1 is mostly a bugfix release. Below are release notes with the links to the exact issues fixed:</p>
Release Notes &#8211; cirQWizard &#8211; Version 1.5.1

<h2>        Bug</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-92'>CQ-92</a>] &#8211;         Stop button on tool paths generation pane doesn&#39;t stop generation</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-130'>CQ-130</a>] &#8211;         Firmware update instability</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-131'>CQ-131</a>] &#8211;         Check for non-empty settings is broken</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-134'>CQ-134</a>] &#8211;         ExcellonParser fails with <span class="caps">NPE</span> if no tool is specified</li>
</ul>

<h2>        New Feature</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-133'>CQ-133</a>] &#8211;         Support for R command in Excellon files</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.5.0 - copper rub out feature]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/08/21/version-1-dot-5-0-copper-rub-out-feature/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-21T23:04:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/08/21/version-1-dot-5-0-copper-rub-out-feature</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.5.0 comes with the long promised copper rub out feature. That&#8217;s an additional step which you can choose to perform after insulation milling (it&#8217;s skipped by default &#8211; check the new <strong>Copper rub out</strong> section in the <strong>Settings</strong> to turn it on).</p>
<p>As opposed to insulation milling, which simply isolates traces on the copper layer, this step completely removes copper from the places on the board, where it&#8217;s not supposed to be according to the layout. This is often required in circuits, involving radio frequencies or high voltages &#8211; unconnected copper alters electrical features of the board in undesired way.</p>
<p>The implementation may not win the prettiest algorithm contest. It might not be the fastest algorithm on Earth either. But at least it&#8217;s here today and it gets the job done. We&#8217;ll address algorithm inefficiencies later down the road.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Major UI revamp in 1.4.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/08/15/major-ui-revamp-in-1-dot-4-0/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-15T14:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/08/15/major-ui-revamp-in-1-dot-4-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This version addresses user interface usability issues which were raised by our users. It rearranges controls in a way that keeps intuitive step-by-step wizard approach appreciated by those who are just getting their feet wet in <span class="caps">PCB</span> milling, but allows for greater flexibility required by more experienced users.</p>
<p>So, the major new features are:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Breadcrumb bar navigation, allowing for direct jumps between application screens (no more <strong>Go back</strong>, <strong>Go back</strong>, <strong>Go back</strong> clicking to get to the screen you want to return to)</li>
	<li><strong>Manual control</strong> popover accessible from every screen of application, allowing to move machine&#8217;s axes as you please</li>
	<li>Predefined locations &#8211; in addition to already existing <strong>Far away</strong>, there&#8217;s now also <strong>Tool change</strong> location. Both of them with all three coordinates: X, Y and Z.</li>
	<li><strong>Settings</strong> popover accessible from operations screens &#8211; you can now change all the settings related to the operation you are currently performing right from the operation screen. No need to go back to settings anymore to change additional passes overlap or pre-feed delay!</li>
</ul>
<p>This version has also seen major code refactoring, paving a way for new exciting features, which were held back by growing code complexity.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Versions 1.3.10 and 1.3.11]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/07/14/versions-1-dot-3-10-and-1-dot-3-11/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-14T14:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/07/14/versions-1-dot-3-10-and-1-dot-3-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These two versions add a possibility to send G-code to the machine directly from cirQWizard. This functionality can be accessed from <strong>Manual Control &#8594; Direct GCode control</strong>.</p>
<p>Version 1.3.10 had a build issue which resulted in broken functionality of firmware flashing. This was fixed in 1.3.11.</p>
<p>Below are release notes for version 1.3.10:</p>
Release Notes &#8211; cirQWizard &#8211; Version 1.3.10
<h2>        New Feature</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-83'>CQ-83</a>] &#8211;         Possibility to send GCode directly to the machine</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Versions 1.3.2-1.3.9]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/06/09/versions-1-dot-3-2-1-dot-3-9/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-09T14:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/06/09/versions-1-dot-3-2-1-dot-3-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve been in such a hurry to release these versions that we didn&#8217;t even blog about them. So, here go the release notes for all these versions. We&#8217;ll try not to postpone blogging about new releases going forward.</p>
<h1>Version 1.3.2</h1>
<h2>        Bug</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-99'>CQ-99</a>] &#8211;         Arcs not supported in contour milling layer</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-100'>CQ-100</a>] &#8211;         Oval apertures not supported on solder paste layer</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.3</h1>
<h2>        Improvement</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-102'>CQ-102</a>] &#8211;         Support for LP parameter in gerbers</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.4</h1>
<h2>        Bug</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-69'>CQ-69</a>] &#8211;         Running gcode without connected machine doesn&#39;t produce an error</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-103'>CQ-103</a>] &#8211;         Flash width is not taken into account when board&#39;s zero point is calculated</li>
</ul>
<h2>        Improvement</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-89'>CQ-89</a>] &#8211;         Improvements of tool path merge algorithm</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.5<br />
<h2>        Bug</h1>
</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-107'>CQ-107</a>] &#8211;         <span class="caps">NPE</span> in Region.getMin()</li>
</ul>
<h2>        Improvement</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-106'>CQ-106</a>] &#8211;         Support for decimal point in Excellon files</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.6<br />
<h2>        Bug</h1>
</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-2'>CQ-2</a>] &#8211;         Incorrect order of screens when drilling holes</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-86'>CQ-86</a>] &#8211;         Zoom shortcuts do not work on Linux</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-104'>CQ-104</a>] &#8211;         Tool paths around polygonal apertures do not take into account tool diameter</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-108'>CQ-108</a>] &#8211;         Additional passes feature broken</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-109'>CQ-109</a>] &#8211;         Parts of tool paths sometimes disappear during merge</li>
</ul>
<h2>        Improvement</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-76'>CQ-76</a>] &#8211;         Separate feed for arcs</li>
</ul>
<h2>        New Feature</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-21'>CQ-21</a>] &#8211;         Reset settings to default</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.7</h1>
<p>Version 1.3.6 was unintentionally released with Mac OS X version built with Java 8. This version corrects this mistake with all of the platforms using Java 7 for build.</p>
<h1>Version 1.3.8</h1>
<h2>        Bug</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-105'>CQ-105</a>] &#8211;         In some cases program generates incorrect toolpaths</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-110'>CQ-110</a>] &#8211;         Elapsed time message on machining screen doesn&#39;t show hours</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-111'>CQ-111</a>] &#8211;         Application icon disappeared</li>
</ul>
<h1>Version 1.3.9<br />
<h2>        Bug</h1>
</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-113'>CQ-113</a>] &#8211;         Phantom tool paths on solder paste layer</li>
</ul>
<h2>        New Feature</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-3'>CQ-3</a>] &#8211;         Visual guidance on offset selection screen</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.3.1 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/04/08/version-1-dot-3-1-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T19:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/04/08/version-1-dot-3-1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.3.1 is mostly a bug fix release. Here is the list of things fixed in this version:</p>
<h2>        Bug</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-17'>CQ-17</a>] &#8211;         Exception on start up when using autodetect</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-30'>CQ-30</a>] &#8211;         Select all command on drilling screen selects holes irrespective of their diameter</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-77'>CQ-77</a>] &#8211;         Tabbing out of &quot;Tool diameter&quot; on machining screen doesn&#39;t trigger regeneration</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-85'>CQ-85</a>] &#8211;         Tool paths cache invalidation is inconsistent</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-90'>CQ-90</a>] &#8211;         Tool paths not regenerated when changing number of passes</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-93'>CQ-93</a>] &#8211;         <span class="caps">NPE</span> in SerialInterfaceFactory.getSerialInterfaces()</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-96'>CQ-96</a>] &#8211;         Empty lines in excellon file cause parser to fail</li>
</ul>
<h2>        Improvement</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-70'>CQ-70</a>] &#8211;         Better visibility for &quot;Go&quot; button on machining screen</li>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-91'>CQ-91</a>] &#8211;         Relabel &quot;Lower &amp; Test&quot; button</li>
</ul>
<h2>        Task</h2>
<ul>
<li>[<a href='https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/browse/CQ-95'>CQ-95</a>] &#8211;         Add target that runs the application to the build.xml</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 1.3.0 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/27/version-1-dot-3-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-27T19:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/27/version-1-dot-3-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 1.3.0 is a feature release, which adds a possibility to request milling tool path generation algorithm to make several passes around traces (or only around pads). This hopefully should decrease the possibility of solder bridges between pads or between pads and ground plane.</p>
<p>Additional passes considerably increase milling time, regardless of whether it&#8217;s pads only or entire traces. But hopefully, there will be more time gained by not having to troubleshoot bridges.</p>
<p>The relevant settings in the <strong>Insulation milling</strong> tab are:</p>
<table class="table table-bordered ">
	<tr>
		<th>Setting </th>
		<th>Meaning </th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td> Additional passes </td>
		<td> Number of additional passes to be generated </td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td> Additional passes overlap </td>
		<td> The overlap between previous pass and each successive pass </td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td> Additional passes around pads only </td>
		<td> Whether to generate additional passes around all traces, or around pads only </td>
	</tr>
</table>
<p>For now, as this feature isn&#8217;t yet thoroughly tested, the default value for <strong>Additional passes</strong> is 0, which effectively disables it. Feel free to experiment and let us know which settings you like most!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Issue tracking system up and running]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/25/issue-tracking-system-up-and-running/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T00:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/25/issue-tracking-system-up-and-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a next step in our effort to make cirQWizard even more open and transparent we&#8217;ve migrated to publicly available issue tracking system.</p>
<p>The system can be accessed at <a href="https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/">https://cirqwizard.atlassian.net/</a> There you can find detailed information about issues addressed in each release, issues scheduled for the next releases, new features we are thinking about and all those annoying bugs no one has time to fix ;)</p>
<p>What&#8217;s even better, after simple registration procedure everyone can contribute to the project &#8211; you can comment on issues, vote for them so that we know which issues are important to you, create new issues reporting bugs you&#8217;ve encountered or suggesting new great features!</p>
<p>Help us make cirQWizard even more awesome!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog goes live &amp; version 1.2.2]]></title>
    <link href="http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/24/blog-goes-live-and-version-1-dot-2-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:18:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cirqwizard.org//blog/2014/03/24/blog-goes-live-and-version-1-dot-2-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the community of cirQWizard users grows, we feel it&#8217;s the right time to add another communication channel to keep everyone up to date on what we have done and what we are up to. So, from now on here we will be blogging about things happening to cirQWizard &#8211; new releases, known problems and workarounds, useful hints and whatever comes to our mind and we feel is appropriate to share.</p>
<p>Needless to say, your comments are much appreciated! Feel free to share your thoughts in comments section below every article.</p>
<p>So, today the news is that the version 1.2.2 is out. That&#8217;s a bug-fix release. The most important bug fixed there was the one that was causing missing segments of the tool paths during generation. This was caused by insufficient memory available to cirQWizard to utilize all of the available <span class="caps">CPU</span> cores. Now the application attempts to reprocess failed part of the board. You would see progress indicator jumping chaotically, as this happening. If this happens to you, you would know cirQWizard is running low on memory. Then it doesn&#8217;t make sense to run that many processing threads. To make more efficient use of your resources you can go to <strong>Settings&#8594;Application</strong> and decrease <strong>Processing threads</strong> value. With a bit of trial and error you can find a value, that would work well for you.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re setting up a public access to the issue tracking system we use to develop cirQWizard. This would give everyone interested in depth information about what exactly was included in the released versions, as well as what we are working on at the moment and what we are thinking about. Stay tuned!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
